David Caldwell

Web Developer

Dayton, Ohio (937)-901-4906 davidjoscaldwell@gmail.com Portfolio Site GitHub LinkedIn

Web Developer with 3 years development experience in the defense industry. Well-versed in front-end and back-end technologies such as Javascript, React, Node, Express, and MongoDb. A strong focus on planning, prototyping, testing, and refining web applications. Committed to learning and using the best tool for the problem at hand.

SKILLS and TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript
- jQuery
- React.js
- Bootstrap5, React-Bootstrap
- Styled-Components
- Responsive Design
- RESTful APIs

- AWS Serverless Functions
- Deploying Apps (Heroku, Netlify)
- WordPress
- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Web Scraping

- Cheerio
- Puppeteer
- Jest and Enzyme
- Unit, Integration, End-to-End Testing
- Git/ Version Control

EXPERIENCE

Part-Time Software Developer/ IT Support - SciTec Inc. Fairborn, OH

June 2017 - April 2020

- Developed a prototype for a complete company website overhaul using WordPress.
- Assisted in the partial automation of the company's hiring process. This included using python to update the company's applicant tracking system and send automated emails to and from the hiring manager.
- Helped manage the logistics and setup of the company's local network through two office moves. This included wiring, testing, and debugging local internet and phone systems.
- Managed the local office inventory with tools like Jira while performing regular data backups and safely discarding old data and unused equipment.

Software Development Intern - SciTec Inc. Fairborn, OH

May 2016 - September 2016

- Created MATLAB functions to analyze data within a Java application, allowing the user to access specific pieces of data.
- Developed a custom output window that logged the activity of a Java application, allowing the user to view the app's internal data flow.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full–Stack Development - CareerFoundry

September 2021 - April 2022

- Heavy focus on HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB.
- Developed multiple applications including front-end apps(jQuery, React.js), back-end APIs(Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB), and a full-stack app using the MERN stack.
- Learned industry best practices such as responsive design and Test Driven Development.

Computer Science - *Mount Vernon Nazarene University*

September 2014 - May 2017

- Focus on Object-oriented languages such as Java and C++/ Data structures and algorithms